Matthew Sisserson

MASisserson

PROFILE

I'm a full stack web application software engineer with 3 years of experience in customer success focused end-toend application development using JavaScript, Python, and a variety of other services. My passion for computer engineering drew me away from my former work in Biochemistry, but I leverage the critical thinking skills I developed there everyday. Most recently, I created Otto, an open-source automated ETL workflow manager built with Express.js, React, and PostgreSQL. On the side, I am currently working on an event management app to meet a friend's administrative needs.

SKILLS

Backend

Node.js, Express.js, Python, Django, Ruby, Golang, SQL, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs

Frontend

TypeScript, Next.js, React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Jest

AWS, Docker, Git, Linux, Bash, Architecture, Infrastructure, Prototypes, Figma, Gaming

EXPERIENCE

Creator, Software Engineer, Otto - www.otto-etl.com *⊘*

2023 – present

Otto is an open-source, web-based, automated ETL workflow manager capable of extracting 200K+ PostgreSQL database rows, transforming that data, and loading it at scheduled intervals.

- Generated a recursive workflow execution algorithm enabling parallel task executions and increasing a workflow's maximum nodes from 5 to 30+
- Implemented real-time workflow execution log and metric streaming to the UI via server-sent events, empowering users to diagnose workflow failures and bottlenecks
- Built a drag-and-drop node-based user interface using React, React Flow and Material UI that allows users to design workflows by creating, connecting and deleting nodes
- Enabled users to join and transform extracted data by constructing a system for acquiring and executing arbitrary user code against multiple sources of data using Node. js VM and Code Mirror 6
- · Containerized application using Docker which allowed installation without setting up databases and environment variables, achieving an 70% reduction in installation and configuration time
- Developed an execution scheduler using Node-Cron that automatically runs workflows at specific intervals and reschedules executions in the event of a network fault or server restart
- Orchestrated a data management system for staging workflow data as it passed through extraction, transformation, and loading steps
- Wrote REST API endpoints that perform CRUD operations on workflow, execution, and metrics resources
- Led stand ups, sprint planning sessions and weekly retrospectives for a four-person remote team
- Authored a comprehensive case study and gave a tech talk on the creation and design of Otto

Software Engineer, Self-employed

2020 - 2023

A few of the projects & technologies used during this time:

- Evently A SaaS event scheduler that collects customer data and sends customer notifications hosted on AWS (Next. js, React, Django, Python, AWS, EC2, S3, IAM)
- QuestBin an application for receiving & debugging webhooks (Express, React, Nginx, DigitalOcean Droplet,
- Binge a database-backed e-commerce app (React, MongoDB, Node)

Laboratory Technician, Hiram College

2015 - 2019

• Developed a custom filter holder and black box which increased spectrophotometer effectiveness by 250% and saved the lab \$20,000 in equipment expenses

EDUCATION